How Hong Kong kicked off a cinematic revolution
Iron Fists and Kung Fu Kicks is a documentary,
history film directed by Serge Ou.
The fantastic story of how an ancient martial art, Chinese kung fu, conquered the world through the hundreds of films that were produced in Hong Kong over the decades,
transformed Western action cinema and inspired the birth of cultural movements such as blaxploitation, hip hop music, parkour and Wakaliwood cinema.
Self, played by Alan Hofmanis.
Self, played by Alien Ness.
Self, played by Amy Johnston.
Self, played by Andre Morgan.
Self, played by Billy Blanks.
Self, played by Brian Camp.
Kung Fu Hustle (Chinese: 功夫; pinyin: Gōngfu; lit.
'Kung Fu') is a 2004 martial arts action comedy film directed, produced and co-written by Stephen Chow, who also stars in the
leading role, alongside Huang Shengyi, Yuen Wah, Yuen Qiu, Danny Chan Kwok-kwan and Leung Siu-lung in prominent roles.
The story revolves around a murderous neighbourhood gang, a poor village with unlikely
heroes and an aspiring gangster's fierce journey to find his true self.
The martial arts choreography is supervised by Yuen Woo-ping.
The film was a co-production between Hong Kong and
Mainland Chinese companies, filmed in Shanghai.
After the commercial success of Shaolin Soccer, its production company, Star Overseas, began
to develop the films with Columbia Pictures Film Production Asia in 2002.
It features a number of retired actors famous for 1970s Hong Kong action cinema and has been compared to
contemporary and influential wuxia films such as Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon and Hero.
The cartoon special effects in the film, accompanied by traditional
Chinese music, are often cited as its most striking feature.
Kung Fu Hustle premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2004, and
released on 23 December 2004 in China and on 25 January 2005 in the United States.
The film received positive reviews and grossed US$17 million in
North America and US$84 million in other regions.
It was tenth on the list of highest-grossing foreign-language films in the United States as
well as the highest-grossing foreign-language film in the country in 2005.
Kung Fu Hustle won numerous awards, including six Hong Kong
Film Awards and five Golden Horse Awards.
The film was re-released in 3D in October 2014 across Asia and North
America, marking the tenth anniversary of the film.
The film explores themes of martial arts, kung fu,
hip-hop, cinema on cinema, movie business.